Hello guys welcome to my channel so today we will
see
how to fill the claim form of ICICI Lord Health Care first of all
you need to
download the form after that
I will explain to you how to fill it the
first option is type of claim means you
want to claim the main expenses of the hospital or you want to claim
some expenses before or after joining the hospital
you will have to select this option and cashless availed
also means if the hospital you joined had
cashless possibility
and whether you want to avail it or not
you will have to select its option here
after that now in A2 name of the patient
here you will have to write the name of the patient
in capital letters every form will have to be
written completely in capital letters and card number and
YC ID of the patient here you will
get the number on the card you will get YC ID of the patient
write the number of the card here
after that
write the gender and date of birth and here
Completed Age: Mapping this date of birth,
fill in their age in years and months and
what is their occupation, that is, whether they are in service or self-
employed, home maker, student or
retired, you will have to fill this and you will have to
put the details of any other medi claim or health insurance in which you were already covered, yes, if
you were in any medical health insurance then
you will have to mention its name here as well
and after that you will have to fill in the current residential
address i.e. all your details, after that you will have to enter
city, state, pin code,
mobile and email, after this
you will have to select the status of vaccination,
if you have taken vaccination then yes and
which vaccination you have taken and after that
you will have to select how many doses of vaccination you have taken
and after this,
whatever policy of yours is health insurance
and if you have got it from the company, then
whatever employee ID of your company will be there, you will have to
write the employee ID here
and here instead of the group company name, you will have to
write the name of your company, if your
insurance is individual then you will have to select it here
In this area, instead of individual retail
policy, you will have to fill its details
and next will be the name of the Prosper
employee. Here, the policy is
given in whose name, that means, imagine if the
company will give you the policy, then the
details of the employee will have to be filled here.
Relationship with the Prosper
means, whatever this patient is,
what will be the employee's relationship, let's say wife and husband
or mother son, you will have to write something like this here
and you will get the current policy number
on the same card and you will have to fill the same card
number here. Keep in mind that
whatever you are filling here will be of the employee,
this is not of the patient but of the main employee.
After that, if the diagnosis is on the
discharge card, that is, what kind of room it was, was it
accidental or was there a delivery report,
some information related to that will have to be written here,
after that you will write the name of the
hospital where you were admitted and
what kind of room category you have taken, was it day
care or single  If it is occupancy twin
sharing or three sharing or something else, then
other will have to be written.
Data of admission when you joined will have to be
written there and with time.
You will also have to write date of discharge
with time. After that, date of injury sustained. If
whatever your claim is is accidental
related
or any disease, you have already detected
that it was some issue. If
you know its date, then you will have to write it here. This is
not mandatory, but if you know about it, then you will have to
fill it.
After that, if the type of injury happened, if it happened
by yourself or due to a road
accident or some other personal matter, then
you will have to fill those details.
Medico legal means here your case or
you have suffered some injury, if it is involved
in any legal matter, then you will have to give its details
here and if it is medico legal, then you will have to give
its details whether to inform the police or not.
If it is so, then its FIR attached copy, whatever it is, will have to be
written and system of medicine respect
You will have to mention Allopathy or AYUSH, Lop
means the regular doctor will be
called Lop, AYUSH means other, like
Ayurvedic, Unani, you will have to
check this here, for other claims in the
purpose of policy or insent means or for
this issue, if you have applied for
health insurance claim for any other policy, then you will have to
mention this no. and if this is yes, then its
details will have to be given here, after that are
you covered under any top additional policy, ssr
no. if there is another top policy, then you will have to
mention its details, if this is yes, then its
details will also have to be given here,
currently covered by any other medical
health care insurance, if the
company has
not given you health insurance, then if you have any
other medical health insurance, then
its details will have to be given here,
if not then you can ignore it, it is
not that important, now from here, the most important thing will be useful for
you, first of all you will have to
write about the amount, where
you will have to write about pre-hospital expenses, if you have
some problem even before joining the hospital  If there is some amount of it, then it will have to be
entered here. When you
were in the hospital, all the expenses incurred will have to be
entered here.
After coming out of the hospital, whatever expenses are incurred will
come here. If there is
some amount of health checkup, then it will come in the health checkup post.
If there are any ambulance charges involved, then the
amount of ambulance charges will have to be
entered here. And if you have some other miscellaneous things, then you will have to
enter the total here.
After this, now if you are
entering the amount in pre-hospital expenses, then you will have to tell
for how many days and what amount you want to
claim, that is, for how many days was the issue for
which you want to claim the expense, it will
remain like this, post-hospitalization
period and you can also leave this option,
it is not that important for you. It will
come here after that. Similarly, if you want to
claim hospital daily cash and maternity, that is, cash for maternity, from
here till here,
you have an option in this, you will have to
fill it, the rest is
not that important, after that whatever you have to do  You will
get bills for every bill, like room rent,
you should remember what is the bill number,
you should have the bill receipt and
another two of the overall building summary, at all
times, whatever is the bill number of the room rent, you will have to
write the bill number and when the bills were
made, if you want to attach the bill then you will have to tick on 'S',
if not then you will have to tick on 'No Attach'
and after that you will have to mention the amount,
you will have to fill all such details, after that
you will have to mention the total amount here, the
amount you want to claim,
after this you will have to check whatever documents you have updated, whether the
claim form is filled, that is, the form
you have said right now, if you upload it then you will have to
click on 'Cancel Cheque', details of the
account in which you are spending the money
and discharge summary yes and all the
details that you
want to attach should be attached by saying 'S'
and do not forget one mistake that
in the age proof, clearly mention that
you have some other document and not the Aadhar card.  You will have to
upload it like driving
license, PAN card or passport and
in the last you will have to enter the date here
from where you will have to mention the place and the
signature of the insurer. Yes, if you are
taking more than 30 days to send the documents, then you will have to mention the reason
why you are late.
After this, whatever details are there, the
hospital will fill it completely, so you will
not need to evolve anything in it,
clearly the hospital will fill it completely and
give it to you. Now these parts are the most
important where you will have to write the name of the patient, the
policy number and the
UID number of the card. If it is
corporate insurance, then the company
details or if you have gone for cashless, then the claim
number. Otherwise, you can ignore this.
After that, mobile and email ID and after that
you will also have to give two valid proofs and a cancelled cheque,
so both will have to be checked.
After that, the bank details of the person in whose account you are depositing the money will have to be
filled here. Do
all this here and that will be enough. This Part
D will be required only if your  The claim
amount may be more than Rs 1 lakh but
as far as I understand you will have to fill Part A and
Part C and Part
B will be filled for you by your hospital of the company and will give it to
you
hopefully and after filling
this form for claiming insurance in the easiest way
you can download Il Take Care App and from there
you will get the possibility of making the claim most easily.